<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Computer Science Knowledge Base</title>
      <link>https://quartz.jzhao.xyz</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Computer Science Knowledge Base</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>🌱Basics/Intro</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/HCI-&-VR/Basics</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/HCI-&-VR/Basics</guid>
    <description>HCI (Human Computer Interactions) is a field of computer science (and interdisciplinary with social sciences) that helps to design and analyze hardware, and software interfaces that better suit people’s needs.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>🌱Basics/Intro</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Hardware/Basics</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Hardware/Basics</guid>
    <description>Hardware is the name we give to the physical components of a computer. The hardware is all the stuff that actually sends the signals (electrical or otherwise) we need to make our computers work.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>RAM</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Hardware/RAM</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Hardware/RAM</guid>
    <description>Volatile vs Persistent Memory (TODO) § … Memory Addressing (TODO) § … Virtual Addressing (TODO) § … Additional Resources § How does Computer Memory Work? 💻🛠 (youtube.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>🌱Basics/Intro</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Networking-&-Webdev/Basics</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Networking-&-Webdev/Basics</guid>
    <description>… OSI § … Additional resources § About early internet The Computer Chronicles - The Internet (1993) (youtube.com) Bill Gates Explains the Internet to Dave (1995) | Letterman (youtube.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>HTTP</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Networking-&-Webdev/HTTP</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Networking-&-Webdev/HTTP</guid>
    <description>HTTP (HyperText Transfer Protocol) is the way most of the web communicates. It’s the system that governs how your computer talks to servers around the world to retrieve webpages, talk to your online calendar, and even send messages in point of sales systems.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Linux</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/OS-&-Firmware/Unix-&-Linux</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/OS-&-Firmware/Unix-&-Linux</guid>
    <description> Info History informs some of the technical information, as such this section will include technical info about linux, and some history. This I think is the best way to talk about linux &amp; unix since often the history informs the technical decisions.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Userspace</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/OS-&-Firmware/Userspace</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/OS-&-Firmware/Userspace</guid>
    <description>This is the good old operating system you know and love. This is where applications, your desktop, and %90 of computing is done. (5) The Layman’s Guide to Linux: User Space - YouTube (Covers most things at once, but I would recommend doing other sections first then come back to this video) Package managers § These systems are designed to help a user manage packages (applications and services that run on an OS).</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Number Systems (binary &amp; hex)</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Binary,-Hexadecimal-and-Number-Systems</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Binary,-Hexadecimal-and-Number-Systems</guid>
    <description>When we count we traditionally use base 10. Base 10 gives us 10 values before we shift digits. We go from 0-9, and then we shift 1 digit left, and start from 0 in the far right column again: 0 1 2 .</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Caching</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Caching</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Caching</guid>
    <description>A cache is basically a system where you store something you know you will need for later. Imagine you work in a bakery. If you wait until someone orders a loaf of bread to cook it, then now every person who comes into your store has to wait for you to cook the loaf before they can leave.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Compression</title>
    <link>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Compression</link>
    <guid>https:/quartz.jzhao.xyz/Programming/Compression</guid>
    <description>Storage space is valuable. Whether it’s memory on someone’s computer that needs to be preserved to keep it running, or space on a drive to keep it from being full.</description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:38:27 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>